CHILD : We lay , my love and I
Beneath the weeping willow
But now alone I lie
And weep beside the tree
Singing " O Willow Waly "
By the tree that weeps with me
Till my lover returns to me
We lay , my love and I
Beneath the weeping willow
But now alone I lie
O willow , I die
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ BIRDS CONTINUE CHIRPING ]
[ QUIET SOBBING , SNIFFLING ]
[ SOBBING CONTINUES ]
[ BIRDS CONTINUE CHIRPING ]
WOMAN : [ WHISPERING ] All I want to do is save the children ...
not destroy them .
More than anything , I love children .
More than anything .
[ WHIMPERING ]
They need affection ...
love ...
someone who will belong to them ...
and to whom they will belong .
MAN : Miss Giddens , may I ask you a somewhat personal question ?
Do you have an imagination ?
Oh ! [ CHUCKLES ]
Oh , yes , I can answer that .
- Yes . - Good .
Truth is very seldom understood by any but imaginative persons ...
and I want to be quite truthful .
I 'm a bachelor ...
but not , I might add , a lonely one .
I spend a great deal of time abroad .
And as for my London life , well , it amuses me ...
but it 's not the sort of amusement that one could suitably share with children .
In brief , Miss Giddens ...
I am a very selfish fellow ...
and the last man alive to be saddled so suddenly and so awkwardly ...
with two orphaned infants .
[ INHALES , SIGHS ] It 's most unfortunate ...
for I have no room for them , neither mentally nor emotionally .
Does that seem quite heartless ?
Honest , but not heartless .
Then the children do not live with you ?
No . They are at my country estate in Bly .
A rather large , rather lonely place .
Still , I 'm sure you 'll agree , the country seems the proper thing for children .
I see from your letter that you are , yourself , the daughter of a country parson ...
and , um ... oh , yes , here it is ...
" More than anything , I love children . "
- Yes . - How remarkable .
For several years now ...
little Miles and Flora ...
Charming names , don 't you think ...
have had only me .
Well , poor brats , they need more than a distant uncle .
Well , of course they need more than a governess .
They need affection and love ...
and someone to whom they can belong and who will belong to them .
You , Miss Giddens .
I feel that you are that person .
Sir , you ...
you do realize that this would be my first position .
What does that signify ...
if I trust you , if you trust me ?
You see , Miss Giddens , the person whom I engage ...
must solemnly promise to accept full and complete responsibility .
She must never trouble me .
Never . Never .
Neither complain nor appeal nor write .
Simply take the whole thing over and ...
leave me alone .
What do you say , Miss Giddens ?
The children , uh ...
- Have they had a governess before ? - Unfortunately .
Not that there was anything wrong with Miss Jessel .
She was an excellent governess and a most respectable woman .
The children quite liked her , especially little Flora .
Oh , which reminds me , be careful not to broach that subject to Flora .
She was so fond of Miss Jessel , and ...
it did come as an appalling shock .
I 'm not certain that I understand you , sir .
- [ CLOCK CHIMING ] - She died .
Yes , just when I thought I 'd got the whole situation settled ...
and everything running smoothly ...
the confounded woman died .
It was all very odd .
I was in Calcutta when it happened ...
and have only now been able to seek a replacement .
Meantime , my nephew had to be sent off to school ...
and the little girl , Flora , is being chaperoned by my housekeeper ...
Mrs. Grose .
Help me , Miss Giddens , for truly I am helpless .
Give me your hand .
Give me your promise .
Well , sir ...
if you are really sure ...
Quite sure , and very grateful .
Only remember , you 're in supreme authority .
Whatever happens , you must handle it alone .
Yes , I 'll try .
I promise you that .
I 'll do everything I can to keep the children happy .
- MISS GIDDENS : Oh , stop . Please stop ! - Whoa there .
If you don 't mind , I think I 'd like to walk from here .
As you wish , miss . Whoa .
Thank you .
WOMAN : Flora !
Flora !
Didn 't you hear ? Someone is calling your name .
No , I don 't think so . I didn 't hear anyone .
Isn 't your name Flora ?
I 'm Miss Giddens .
Yes , I know . You 're my new governess .
I 've been watching the road , waiting for you .
- Are you afraid of reptiles ? - That rather depends . Why ?
Because I 've got one in my pocket , and he 's very eager to meet you .
Well , in that case , by all means .
- [ SIGHS ] - His name is Rupert .
- Oh , a tortoise . - We love each other .
- Yes , I can see that you 're very close . - Very .
There , now you 've met Miss Giddens .
But Rupert isn 't the only one .
I mean , ever since my uncle wrote ...
we 've all been waiting and waiting for you to come .
Oh , we have been excited .
So have I. I 've been very excited indeed .
Not as excited as we have . And not as excited as Mrs. Grose .
She 's cleaned and cleaned and had all the windows washed .
Just imagine ... 134 windows !
- All that for me ? - Yes . And I helped !
- Oh , we will have fun together , won 't we ? - Yes , we will , dear .
Oh , Mrs. Grose , she 's here ! And she isn 't afraid of reptiles .
And that 's more than can be said of me , isn 't it ? [ LAUGHS ]
[ CHUCKLES ] I walked from the gate .
I ... I wanted to see it all .
[ CHUCKLES ] I 'm glad to see you , Miss Giddens .
Really , I 'm glad .
Oh , do please come in .
Thank you . You 're very kind .
- Oh ! - Now , I expect you 'd like a cup of tea .
- Thank you . - But not you , Miss Flora .
Now , you know you 're not allowed in the house with that toad or turtle ...
or whatever it is .
- Go on . Run along . Off you go . - Oh , all right .
I had no idea .
I never imagined ...
Oh , I 'm so sorry .
That 's all right , miss . It 's always happening .
I never imagined it would be so beautiful .
Well , we do our best .
Though half the rooms are empty now ... locked and empty .
All the same , it 's too big , a job to keep clean .
But what I always say is , it 's a heaven for children .
Oh , yes , a heaven !
And what an enchanting child she is .
There 's not another like her .
Though , mind you , she has her ways . You have your work cut out .
I don 't doubt .
But she seems ... Well , she certainly looks angelic .
Well , she is too .
But she does like to wander , to go off by herself .
- We 're always hunting her . - Oh , yes . I heard you .
Just now , as I was coming through the garden , I heard you call her name .
Oh , not me , miss .
Perhaps it was Anna or Cook .
Well , someone .
Sit down , miss , and have your tea .
Mmm , it 'll be dark in here soon .
I 'll get Anna to bring some lamps .
Miss Giddens ?
[ WHISPERS ] Miss Giddens ! Has she gone ?
Yes , for the moment .
You don 't mind Rupert sharing a bit of your cake , now , do you ?
Watch out . He 'll grow too fat to fit your pocket .
- I have a pony too . - Oh .
He isn 't really mine . He belongs to Miles .
Miles is my brother , you know . He 's away at school .
You must miss him very much .
Well , he 'll be coming home soon .
Not , I should think , until the holidays .
Time you went upstairs and got ready for your bath , Miss Flora .
Promise , now , you won 't go away .
I expect to be here for a very long time .
And to think what qualms I had .
I was so afraid .
- Afraid , miss ? - I couldn 't make up my mind .
Should I accept this post , or shouldn 't I ?
Well , miss , I 'm sure I 'm very glad you did .
After all , I didn 't have much choice .
Their uncle is most persuasive .
[ LAUGHING ] And don 't I know it .
Many 's the time he 's worked his magic on me .
Even when he was a boy he could twist you around his finger ...
and the children are the same way .
He doesn 't come down here very often ?
Well , he likes the town life .
He always was a very popular gentleman .
And what 's the good of being popular down here ...
with only the children and the pigeons and me ?
- Mrs. Grose ? - Yes , miss ?
- What was she like ? - Who , miss ?
The other governess . The one who died .
Who , Miss Jessel ? Oh , she was a young woman .
Some thought her pretty , and , well , I suppose she was .
But not as pretty as you , miss .
Not by half .
He seems to prefer them young and pretty .
He did . He had the devil 's own eye ...
I mean , that 's his way , the master 's .
- But of whom did you speak first ? - Why , the master , of course .
There 's nobody else , miss . Nobody at all .
[ BOTH LAUGHING ]
Be careful , dear , or you 'll splash Miss Giddens !
And is the other one just as remarkable ? Is he too as enchanting ?
Well , if you like this one ...
you should be quite carried away by Master Miles .
I seem to be carried away quite easily . That 's what happened to me in London .
Miles is coming ! Miles is coming !
Stuff and nonsense . You know very well Miles is at school .
- Now , hold still . - [ BOTH LAUGHING ]
[ CLOCK CHIMING ]
I 've got a little bed in your room . It 's got curtains .
- How nice . - Yes .
Mrs. Grose wanted to give you a big room ...
but I said , " She 'll only be there when she 's asleep . "
Big rooms get bigger at night . Do you know that ?
- Do they ? - Mrs. Grose doesn 't know .
[ WHISPERS ] She shuts her eyes in the dark .
[ LAUGHS ] I think that 's silly . I always look in the dark .
Do you ? And what do you see ?
There are a lot of empty rooms . I said , to Mrs. Grose ...
" I wish there was some way of sleeping in several rooms at once . "
Mrs. Grose was quite startled by the thought .
- I don 't wonder ! - " Stuff and nonsense , " she said .
- " Stuff and nonsense . " - [ BOTH LAUGH ]
Now I lay me down to sleep . I pray the Lord my soul to keep ...
- Why can 't Rupert sleep with me ? - Because you might roll over ...
- and crush him . - Crush a tortoise ?
- Now finish your prayers , dear . - If I should wake before I ...
If I should die before I wake , I pray the Lord my soul to take . Amen .
Miss Giddens , where would the Lord take my soul to ?
- To heaven . - Are you certain ?
Yes , of course , because you 're a very , very good girl .
But I might not be . And if I weren 't ,
wouldn 't the Lord just leave me here to walk around ?
Isn 't that what happens to some people ?
[ LOUD SCREECHING ]
Whatever was that ?
- [ SCREECHING CONTINUES ] - I 'm sure something 's been hurt .
An animal .
We must pretend we didn 't hear it . That 's what Mrs. Grose says .
- Pretend ? - Then we won 't imagine things .
Sometimes one can 't help ... imagining things .
[ MOANS ]
[ SIGHS , MOANING CONTINUES ]
[ HUMMING " O WILLOW WALY " ]
[ STOPS ]
[ RESUMES ]
FLORA : By the tree that weeps with me
Singing " O Willow Waly "
- Till my lover ... - You should be outdoors on a day like this .
I was just practicing , Mrs. Grose .
- Have you seen Miss Giddens , my lamb ? - I 'm out here , Mrs. Grose .
Oh !
There 's some letters for you , miss .
- Oh , thank you . - Oh , please , can I help you read them ?
- Yes , if you like . - Which first ?
Now , how can I tell ?
- Then I shall choose . - All right .
Here .
This one 's from my sister .
Oh , look , dear .
Here 's a picture of me and my family together .
- Am I in it ? - How could you be ? It 's of my family .
Oh .
- Now this one . - It 's from London .
- Is it from my uncle ? - Yes , I think it is .
You do look pleased .
Is he coming to see us ?
No , dear . He 's sent me a letter from Miles 's school .
- Flora ? - Yes , Miss Giddens , dear ?
Didn 't you say last night that Miles was coming home ?
Oh , look .
It 's a lovely spider ...
and it 's eating a butterfly .
Mrs. Grose ?
Here 's a letter their uncle has forwarded without opening .
It 's from Miles 's school .
He just wrote on the envelope , " Am off to Italy for the summer .
This is from Miles 's headmaster . Deal with it without bothering me . "
- That 's just his way , miss . - But how am I to deal with it ?
Miles has been dismissed from school .
- Dismissed ? - Sent home .
Expelled .
But what has he done ? What do the gentlemen say ?
They go into no detail . They simply say ...
Here . Read it .
Read it for yourself .
It 's no good , miss . I never learned .
Oh , I 'm sorry . I didn 't realize .
They say that it is impossible to keep him .
Why ?
That he is ...
an injury to the others .
Master Miles ? Him , an injury ?
Oh , stuff and nonsense .
You might as well think ill of Miss Flora , bless her .
- You 've never known him to be bad ? - Oh , I wouldn 't say that .
You mean you like a boy with spirit .
Well , so do I , but not to the degree to ...
contaminate .
To what ?
To corrupt .
Master Miles ?
[ LAUGHING ] Oh , miss , are you afraid he 'll corrupt you ?
Miles is coming ! Miles is coming ! Miles is coming !
CONDUCTOR : Bly ! Bly station !
Miles ! Miles !
[ LAUGHS ] Miles .
- You 're Miss Giddens , aren 't you ? - Yes .
How do you do ?
Oh , thank you , Miles .
FLORA : She 's our new governess , Miles , and she 's awfully nice .
I hope Miles will agree .
- Come on . - [ TRAIN WHISTLE TOOTS ]
Nothing 's changed .
Oh , I 've been longing for these holidays .
Holidays ?
Longing to see Bly and Mrs. Grose and Flora .
And you . Flora wrote and told me you were coming .
Did you have a good term at school ?
Look , Miles ! There 's the lake !
MILES : Oh , it is nice to be back .
I hope you won 't be lonely ...
with just Flora and Mrs. Grose and me .
Were you happy at school ?
May I tell you something ?
Yes , Miles , of course .
I think you 're far too pretty to be a governess .
And I think you 're far too young to be such a deceitful flatterer .
[ CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
- [ LAUGHING ] - Dearest Mrs. Grose !
- It is nice to be home . - Stop ! Stop ! You 'll have me out of breath !
It 's all just the same .
Somehow ... I don 't know ... I was afraid it might be different .
Oh , nothing ever changes here , Master Miles .
You look a bit thin , though . We 'll have to fatten you up .
Oh , Miles , you haven 't seen the pony !
- May we ? - Yes , of course !
Come on !
[ LAUGHS ]
Well , miss ?
It 's just as you said . Charm seems to run in the family .
And that cruel letter ?
It must be a misunderstanding , a mistake .
Yes , a mistake .
So , uh , what will you say to Master Miles ?
I shall have it out with him later on .
That can 't be avoided . But not now .
I 'm not going to spoil his homecoming because of some silly schoolteacher .
Oh , yes , miss .
Oh , I ... I 'm so thankful we 're not to have trouble .
Dear Mrs. Grose , what a comfort you are .
MILES : Why don 't you come in , Miss Giddens .
How did you know I was there ?
This is a very old house . Things creak .
And anyway , I saw the light from your candle under the door .
You should be asleep .
- I 'm much too excited . - Excited ?
By being home . By seeing Flora .
And meeting you .
Besides , I like to lie awake .
That 's a very bad habit , Miles .
- Is it ? - Yes .
What do you think about while you 're lying awake ?
Oh , a world of different things .
And tonight ...
were you , perhaps , thinking about school ?
Oh , no . All that seems very far away .
Miles ...
you do know that you will not be allowed to go back .
You realize that it is a very serious matter ...
for a boy to be expelled from school .
I can 't think what your uncle will say .
Can 't you ? I can .
He 'll say , " Don 't bother me . I 'm too busy . "
- Miles , that 's not true . - Isn 't it ?
You 've met him , haven 't you ? You know what he 's like .
He doesn 't care about me or Flora .
He doesn 't care what happens to us .
Miles , dear , you mustn 't believe that .
Your uncle has ...
Well , he has ... a great many responsibilities and not enough time ...
To waste any on us ?
I understand .
It 's a bit sad though ...
when people don 't have time for you .
Oh , I have , Miles .
I have time .
And I care .
And , Miles , if there 's something wrong about school ...
if there 's something you want to tell me ...
Miles , dear Miles ...
can 't you see that I want to help you ?
Trust me .
[ GASPS ]
The candle 's gone out .
Don 't be frightened . It was only the wind , my dear . The wind blew it out .
- FLORA : We lay , my love and I - [ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
Beneath a weeping willow
But now alone I lie
And weep beside the tree
Singing " O Willow Waly "
By the tree
That weeps with me
Singing " O Willow Waly "
Till my lover returns ...
- [ STOPS ] - [ BIRDS CEASE CHIRPING ]
- [ BIRDS RESUME CHIRPING ] - We lay , my love and I
Beneath a weeping willow
But now alone I lie
O willow , I die
[ COOING ]
[ FLIES BUZZING ]
Miles .
How long have you been here ?
I don 't know ... 20 minutes , half an hour .
- Oh , then you must have seen him . - Who ?
The man who was standing here on the tower .
I 've been quite alone , except for my greedy friends .
Well , that can 't be true .
Not two minutes ago I saw a man standing exactly here .
Perhaps it was me .
No , no , it was a man .
He was looking at me .
I expect you imagined it .
Or else ... Oh , dear .
I hope you won 't have to wear spectacles .
You 're much too pretty for that .
Oh , yes , I expect I 'm tired .
I haven 't been sleeping well .
I know .
Flora told me .
She says you make little groans and moans all night .
Of course , one can never believe Flora .
She invents things , imagines them .
You mean , like poor , silly Miss Giddens ?
[ LAUGHS ]
[ KISSES ]
Miss , would these , by any chance , be yours ?
Scissors . The gardener brought them up . He said he found them in the garden .
I must have dropped them this morning when I ... whilst I was cutting roses .
And just left them there . [ CHUCKLES ]
I 'm afraid today isn 't altogether my day .
I seem to be at sixes and sevens .
Well , miss , you 've never been away from home before .
A strange place , new responsibilities .
- Takes a bit of getting used to ... - Mrs. Grose .
Is there anyone living here that I don 't know about ?
- Living here ? - In the house , I mean .
I 've met the two maids , the cook and her husband , the gardener ...
and I was just wondering if there was someone I hadn 't met .
Bless you , miss , I wish there were . We could use another pair of hands .
- [ FOOTSTEPS RUNNING ] - Oh , hurry ! Do come !
You must see ! Miles is giving an " expedition ! "
Oh , come ! You must see ! He 's awfully brave !
[ WHINNYING ]
Miles !
Flora , watch me ! [ LAUGHING ]
- Miles ! - [ WIND BLOWING ]
[ BIRDS SQUAWKING ]
Miles ?
I didn 't know you were watching .
That was very clever , Miles .
Do look , Miss Giddens . I can draw too .
Miles isn 't the only one who can draw .
Oh , yes . Now I see . It 's lovely . A vase of flowers .
Goodness , no . It 's a thunderstorm .
- See the clouds and the lightning ? - Oh , yes , dear .
Yes , well , I 'm sure it 's very original . Perhaps you 'll grow up to be ...
- a famous artist . - Did you hear that , Miles ?
Yes , dear . But Miss Giddens is merely being polite .
Tell me , Miss Giddens , what do you think I might grow up to be ?
Anything you want .
There 's nothing I want to be ...
except what I am ... a boy living at Bly .
Oh , if only everything could go on just as it is now .
I love this house .
Don 't you , Miss Giddens ?
It 's very beautiful .
And so large .
I expect it 's the biggest house in England .
The whole world , actually .
Oh , hardly the whole world , Flora .
Your house , where you used to live ... was that a big house too ?
No , it was very small , I 'm afraid .
- How small ? - Very , very small .
Too small for you to have secrets ?
Well , secrets were a bit difficult .
- FLORA : But possible ? - Not for long .
Secrets require a privacy that our little home did not provide .
- Did you play games in your house ? - No .
We had to be quiet , usually , because my father was preparing his sermon .
But if he went out , we 'd play hide-and-seek all over the house .
Oh , lovely !
- Let 's do that ! - All right .
You hide , and I 'll seek .
We can go all over the house , can 't we ?
- Everywhere , I mean . - Yes , I should think so .
[ CLOCK CHIMING ]
Oh . Where are the children going ? It 's their bedtime .
Yes , I know .
But I thought , just one little game and then right to bed they 'll go .
Oh , they 've won you over , miss , already , I can see .
They have indeed .
- FLORA : We 're ready ! - I 'm coming !
[ CHUCKLES ]
Anna ?
MILES : Miss Giddens !
[ GEARS SPINNING ]
[ MUSIC BOX : " O WILLOW WALY " ]
[ DOOR HINGES CREAKING ]
- [ GASPS ] - You 'd never have found me if I hadn 't pounced on you !
- Did I frighten you ? - Yes , a bit .
- Now you 're my prisoner . - Oh , Miles ! Let me go .
- Why ? - You 're hurting me .
- Am I ? - Yes , Miles . Please let me go .
- But why ? - I told you . You 're hurting me .
- Miles , I mean it . - Do you ?
- Oh , you 've found it ! I 've missed it so . - [ MUSIC BOX ]
Mrs. Grose must have hidden it here .
- Now it 's your turn to hide . - Hurry ! Run !
All right .
Now where ? Oh , where shall I hide ?
Wherever you like . We 'll count a hundred .
One , two , three ...
TOGETHER : four , five , six , seven , eight ...
nine , 10 , 11 ...
- [ WIND RUSTLING ] - [ BIRD CALLING ]
[ FLORA , MILES LAUGHING ]
FLORA : Miss Giddens !
Where are you ?
[ SCREAMS , GASPS ]
[ BIRD SQUAWKING ]
MRS. GROSE : Miss ? Miss Giddens ?
Whatever are you doing there , miss ?
Heavens , child , you 're white as milk .
I saw him ! Don 't tell me I didn 't , because I did .
- I saw him staring . - Who , miss ?
- The same man ... the man on the tower . - The tower ?
But now , just now , he was staring past me into the house ...
as if he were hunting someone .
- What 's he like , miss ? - He had dark , curling hair .
- And the hardest , the coldest eyes . - Is he ...
- Would you say he was very handsome ? - Oh yes . Handsome and obscene .
But I 've seen him before . Yes , he ...
I know where I 've seen him . A picture . There 's a picture of him .
A miniature in a cracked glass in the attic .
- I 'll show you . - It can 't be .
- It can 't be ? You know him . - Quint .
- Peter Quint , the master 's valet . - But you said ...
Yes , miss . You see , he 's dead . Quint is dead .
[ GASPS ] Dead ?
- [ LAUGHING ] - [ MUSIC BOX ]
[ LAUGHING CONTINUES , FADES ]
[ MOANING ]
[ THUNDER CRASHING , RUMBLING ]
[ SCREECHING ]
[ SCREECHING CONTINUES ]
Your pencil does have the most terrible squeak , Flora .
It does , doesn 't it ? But I can 't help it , you know .
Can 't you ? I thought you were doing it on purpose .
She is .
- Stop it ! Stop begging ! - I 'm not begging !
Yes , you are ! You 're begging for attention !
- [ SCREAMS , SOBBING ] - There you are , begging again .
First for attention , now for affection .
- Stop it , Flora ! - Now , Miles . Hush , Miles .
Oh , darling . Oh , poor darling Flora .
There , now . Look , I 've made you cry .
Oh , what a hateful , what a grumpy old governess you have .
You 're not grumpy at all .
Of course you 're not . Though I wouldn 't wonder if you were .
Nor would I , with everything so horrible .
- [ SNIFFLING ] - Horrible ?
Why , yes . You know , the rain .
Not being able to go out in the garden .
My squeaky pencil and me ... I wasn 't even trying to be good .
Oh , but you are good .
You both are .
I know what .
Let 's put away our books and let 's pretend it 's Flora 's birthday .
- Oh , yes ! - All right , Flora , it 's your birthday .
- What would you like to do ? - Have a party .
- A costume party . - That 's a splendid idea !
- Miles and I 'll go get all dressed up . - May we ?
- Yes , of course you may . - Come along then , Flora .
FLORA : Oh , good !
[ DOOR OPENS ]
- Hurry , hurry , hurry ! - Where are you going ?
- To dress up ! You said we might ! - Well , I 'll come with you .
No ! Then there 'd be no surprise ! You wait downstairs ! We won 't be long !
FLORA : Hurry , hurry , hurry , hurry !
I 've let them go .
- Go where , miss ? - Oh !
Oh , I 've let the children go .
Upstairs , to the attic , perhaps .
- Alone . - [ LAUGHS ]
- Is that all ? They 'll come to no harm . - I can 't .
I can 't leave them alone , not after the other night .
As for the other night , miss , put it out of your mind .
Pretend it was part of a dream , hich perhaps it was .
A dream ? Don 't you think I want to believe that ?
That it was just the darkness , a nightmare ?
But it 's no longer dark . It 's daylight . And I know I saw him .
A man , or something that once was a man ...
peering in through the window , looking for someone .
And if it isn 't true , if I didn 't see him ...
how could I have described him so accurately ?
Well , you had seen his picture .
Really , miss , you 're upsetting yourself over nothing .
You said he was the valet ?
Yes , but when the master left ...
Quint was alone with us , in charge .
Tell me , how did he die ?
Quint ?
Out there , miss , on those very steps .
It was winter .
The coldest , blackest winter 's night .
The steps were icy .
Quint , he came home late , after we were all abed .
Late , and full of drink .
There was a wound on his head , as if he 'd slipped ...
as if he 'd fallen out there in the dark .
I can 't forget his eyes .
They were open , filled with surprise ...
with pain , like the eyes of a fox I once saw ...
a fox the dogs had hunted down .
But it was an accident ?
He was a peculiar man .
There were things in his life that could account for violence done him ...
vicious things ...
Well , it doesn 't do to speak ill of the dead .
The children never mention him ?
Oh , no , miss , and neither must you ... not to them .
You see , miss , it was Master Miles that found him .
Oh , that poor little boy .
If you could have heard his screams ...
seen the way he clung to him and begged him to speak ...
That poor little boy worshipped Quint .
Worshipped him ? That man ? Miles ?
You didn 't know Quint , miss .
Such power he had over people .
You can 't blame the child .
A lonely boy with no father .
Quint took advantage , that 's all .
It made me sick to see Miles trotting after him like a little dog .
They were always together .
- [ MUSIC BOX ] - MILES : Quiet , everyone .
The entertainment is about to commence .
Oh , look , miss .
I borrowed your pin cushion .
I hope you don 't mind .
Miss Giddens , dear , would you sit there ?
And , Mrs. Grose , would you sit there too ?
And now Miles will recite to you .
A poem .
What shall I sing to my lord from my window ?
What shall I sing , for my lord will not stay ?
What shall I sing , for my lord will not listen ?
Where shall I go , for my lord is away ?
Whom shall I love when the moon is arisen ?
Gone is my lord ...
and the grave is his prison .
What shall I say when my lord comes a-calling ?
What shall I say when he knocks on my door ?
What shall I say when his feet enter softly ...
leaving the marks of his grave on my floor ?
Enter , my lord .
Come from your prison .
Come from your grave ...
for the moon is arisen .
[ WHISPERS ] Welcome , my lord .
[ WHISPERS ] Look at that .
- What , miss ? - I was afraid for them .
But what if he knows ? What if Miles knows ?
Knows what , Miss Giddens , dear ?
You think I 'm imagining it ...
and yet just now you yourself saw and heard Miles ...
Playing a game .
You told me Quint and Miles were always together .
But Master Miles wasn 't to blame for that .
- Yes , but couldn 't you have stopped it ? - I wasn 't in charge , miss .
It wasn 't for me to question the master 's arrangements .
The master put Quint in charge here .
Besides , no one could go against Quint .
You were afraid of him ?
But what of Miss Jessel ?
Couldn 't she have done something ?
Or was she afraid of him too ?
Not at first . At least ...
In the beginning , when she first came here , she was always happy and smiling .
Very fond of music she was ...
and dancing .
She and Miss Flora used to dance together , dance by the hour .
But she changed .
Oh , yes , she changed .
'T was hard to believe ...
her being an educated young lady and Quint being ...
- [ MILES LAUGHING ] - well , what he was .
[ FLORA SCREAMING ] Stop it , Miles ! Stop it !
You see ? I knew they 'd be overexcited . It 's long past their bedtime .
Yes , but what did you mean about Quint and Miss Jessel ?
Look , miss , they 're dead , gone .
There 's no point in telling tales of what 's over and done with .
Over and done with ?
Yes , but is it ?
[ FLORA , MILES LAUGHING ]
MILES : Let go , Flora . You 'll fall in .
FLORA : But I want to row the boat .
Silly . You know you can 't .
Miss Giddens , tell Miles to let me row .
I will , when you 're a little older .
But it 's too heavy for you now .
I don 't care . I 've got a boat of my own anyway .
[ GOOSE HONKING ]
[ SIGHS ]
Heavenly , warm sun .
It 's almost hot .
I like it when it 's hot .
- Do you know what Miles told me once ? - No , dear . What ?
He said that once , when he was on the lake , he could see a hand waving on the bottom .
But Mrs. Grose said , " Stuff and nonsense ! Stuff and nonsense ! "
Miss Giddens , can tortoises swim ?
No , dear .
I thought perhaps they couldn 't .
[ HUMMING " O WILLOW WALY " ]
[ CONTINUES ]
Flora , where did you learn that song ?
I don 't think I remember .
[ RESUMES HUMMING ]
It 's the song from the music box , isn 't it ?
Isn 't it ?
[ CONTINUES ]
MISS GIDDENS : Flora !
Who is it ?
Over there .
Oh , goodness , miss , you gave me quite a turn sitting there in the dark .
- And where are the children ? - Upstairs with Anna .
I wanted to be by myself for a while , to think .
Well , miss , I 'm sure a little light will make your thoughts more cheerful .
Mrs. Grose ? There are two of them .
I beg your pardon ?
Two of those abominations .
Today , down by the lake ...
there in the broad sunlight ...
I saw the other one .
- The other one ? - A woman dressed in black .
- Miss Jessel . - Oh , but Miss Jessel 's dead .
She died , why , almost a year ago .
Huh . Almost a year ago .
Almost a year .
Flora saw her too .
- Did she tell you so ? - No , of course not .
She lied to me . Well , it amounted to a lie .
Oh , now , miss , I 've never known either of the children to tell lies .
- Why would they ? - Why ?
Because they are both playing ...
or being made to play some monstrous game .
I can 't pretend to understand what its purpose is .
I only know that it is happening .
Something secretive and whispery ...
and indecent .
I tell you , believe me , the children are in dreadful peril .
Well , what are we to do ?
Then you do believe me ?
You don 't think I 'm imagining it ?
- I believe you , miss . - Oh , thank God . Thank God .
I 've been so frightened . I 've felt so alone .
But together , with you to help me ...
Oh , yes , miss , I 'll help you . Only tell me how .
Yes .
We must try to learn what it is these horrors want .
Think , Mrs. Grose . The answer must lie in the past .
Were Quint and Miss Jessel in love ?
They were in love , weren 't they ?
Love ? Oh , I suppose that 's what she called it .
But it was more like a sickness ...
a fever that leaves the body burned out and dry .
There was no cruelty she wouldn 't suffer .
If he struck her ... Oh , yes , and I 've seen him knock her to the floor ...
she 'd look at him as though she wanted the weight of his hand .
No pride , no shame .
Crawl to him on her hands and knees , she would .
And him laughing at her . Such a savage laugh he had .
Oh , it hurts me to remember .
Bad she was , but no woman could have suffered more .
A person ought to keep quiet about it .
You must tell me .
Oh , miss , there 's things I 've seen I ... I 'm ashamed to say .
Go on .
Rooms ...
used by daylight ...
as though they were dark woods .
They didn 't care that you saw them ?
And the children ?
I can 't say , miss . I ... I don 't know what the children saw .
But they used to follow Quint and Miss Jessel ...
trailing along behind hand in hand , whispering .
There was too much whispering in this house , miss .
Oh , yes , I can imagine .
Yes , I can imagine what sort of things ...
they whispered about .
Quint , Miles . I can hear them together .
But there was nothing wrong in Master Miles wanting to be with Quint .
Quint taught him to ride and took him walking .
- The poor lad needed someone to ... - To corrupt him ?
But Master Miles is a good boy , miss .
- There 's nothing wicked in him . - Unless he 's deceiving us .
Unless they 're both deceiving us .
- The innocents . - Innocents they are , miss .
It 's not fair . You have no right to accuse them of ...
Oh , forgive me , Mrs. Grose . I 'm not accusing .
I 'm just trying to put it together , to understand .
Tell me , were the children happy ?
Oh , they seemed to be . The same as now .
But sometimes I used to wonder if they really cared for them , those two ...
or if they weren 't just using them .
Using them ?
Yes , of course they were ...
and still are .
And in the end , what happened to her , Miss Jessel ?
Oh , that was pitiful .
When Quint was found , she went into blackest mourning .
Her , that should have hated the man .
She grieved till there was something crazy in her eyes .
Never slept . Never ate .
I used to hear her wandering about all over the house , sobbing .
Couldn 't go on .
Finally she died .
Here ? At Bly ? But of what did she die ?
Well , I suppose you might say a broken heart .
Excuse me , miss . They 're in bed now .
All scrubbed and nice and waiting for you to hear their prayers .
Thank you , Anna . I shall be up in a moment .
- [ DOOR CLOSES ] - One thing more before I go .
- Yes , miss ? - Our local vicar , what sort of man is he ?
The Reverend Fennel ? Oh , he 's a very fine sort of gentleman , miss .
Oh , but , miss , I wouldn 't do that . I ... I mean ,
if you were thinking of discussing with the vicar what we have been discussing ...
oh , I wouldn 't , miss .
- Why not ? - Well , it might cause talk , a scandal .
Haven 't we worse to fear than a scandal ?
But what good would it do , miss , telling the vicar our secrets ? He can 't help us .
He 's perhaps the only one who can .
[ MOANING ]
MRS. GROSE : What good would it do , miss , telling the vicar our secrets ?
He can 't help us .
MISS GIDDENS : Only remember , you are in supreme authority .
Shh . Flora , it 's a secret .
You must remember it 's a secret .
[ CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
Watch her .
- [ CHILDREN LAUGHING ] - Flora , it 's a secret . It 's a secret .
[ LAUGHING ]
[ WHISPERING , INDISTINCT ]
[ WINGS FLAPPING ]
It 's a secret . A secret .
[ MUSIC BOX ]
[ BELL TOLLING ]
- [ CHILDREN LAUGHING ] - I 've made up my mind .
Right after church , I shall take the next train to London and see their uncle .
- He must have returned . - But why , miss ? Why now ?
Because I ... We can go on no longer without help .
I know you 're almost sick with worry , but accept for odd times ...
you can 't say the children haven 't been good .
But they haven 't been good , merely easy to live with .
Because they are not living with us . We have no part in their real life .
Dear Mrs. Grose , I know it 's hard for you to think wrong of those children ...
but there are things that I haven 't told you ...
that I can 't bring myself to tell even you .
- [ TOLLING CONTINUES ] - Look at them .
What do you think they 're saying ?
Well , I don 't know , miss . Just children 's talk .
They 're talking about them .
Talking horrors .
So far these monsters have kept their distance .
Only been seen in high places ...
through windows , across the lake .
But they intend coming closer . And if they do ...
- What will you say to the master ? - Well , what can I say ?
That his house is being poisoned ?
That the children are a pair of calculating liars ?
That they have friends who would frighten them out of their lives ...
if they weren 't deeply and forever bound to them ?
Oh , yes , I know , he 'll think I 'm insane ...
or that it 's some stupid trick to get him to notice me .
Oh , I wish there was something I could do to help .
There is . Have you told me everything ?
If I am to convince their uncle , I must have the truth .
All the truth .
How did Miss Jessel die ?
Please , miss , we 'll be late .
[ TOLLING STOPS ]
How did she die ?
[ ORGAN ]
In wickedness .
She put an end to herself . She was found in the lake , drowned .
Oh , I 'm sorry , miss . I ... I should never have told you .
I 'm glad you did .
Oh , go in , Mrs. Grose . I 'll follow you in a moment .
[ ORGAN CONTINUES ]
Flora .
I do wish you wouldn 't go , miss . It seems wrong somehow , your hurrying off like this .
I 'm left with no choice . Thank you , Mrs. Grose .
There 's nothing else to be done ...
except to go to their uncle , tell him everything and force him to understand .
- Did you order the carriage for me ? - I did , miss .
I 'll go and see if it 's come around . I 'll get someone to take your luggage down .
Thank you . I shall be in the schoolroom .
[ WOMAN SOBBING ]
[ SOBBING CONTINUES ]
MRS. GROSE : Miss Giddens ?
Miss Giddens ?
[ KNOCKS ]
Are you ready , miss ?
I 'm not going .
Everything has changed .
Are you ill ?
- Where are the children ? - Anna 's giving them their milk .
The carriage is ready , miss .
From now on , we must never let them out of our sight .
We can 't take the slightest chance .
Of what ?
She was here .
She was waiting for me .
Who ?
- She spoke . - She spoke ?
It came to that .
Oh , I could feel pity for her ...
if she herself were not so pitiless .
And hungry . Hungry for him .
For his arms ...
and his lips .
But she can only reach him ...
they can only reach each other by entering the souls of the children ...
and possessing them .
The children are possessed .
They live and know ...
and share this hell .
Then surely you must tell the master .
I can 't leave them now .
I shall write to him and insist upon his coming down here .
But even if he chooses to ignore me ...
with or without his help , I think I know how we can save them .
Yes , miss ?
They must be made to admit what is happening .
One word , one word of the truth from these children ...
and we can cast out those devils forever .
I pray to God you 're right , miss .
[ CLOCK TICKING ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ TICKING CONTINUES ]
[ PIANO ]
WOMAN : Shh .
WOMAN : Softly . The children are listening .
[ TICKING CONTINUES ]
[ WOMAN LAUGHING ]
[ FLOOR CREAKING ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ GROSE 'S VOICE ECHOING ] He had a wound on his head as if he 'd slipped .
I can 't forget his eyes ... they were open .
[ MILES 'S VOICE ECHOING ] What shall I say when his feet enter softly ...
leaving the marks of his grave on my floor ?
[ CREAKING ]
WOMAN 'S VOICE : Kiss me . Kiss me .
Kiss me . Kiss me . Kiss me .
[ WIND HOWLING ]
[ WOMAN LAUGHING ]
[ JIGGLING DOORKNOB ]
[ MAN 'S VOICE ECHOING ] Look at the children .
Look at the children .
[ WOMAN LAUGHING ]
WOMAN 'S VOICE : You 're hurting me .
[ DOOR CREAKS , CLOSES ]
[ WOMAN LAUGHING ]
[ ECHOING CLATTER ]
[ WOMAN 'S VOICE ECHOING ] The children are watching .
- The children are watching . - [ JIGGLES DOORKNOB ]
The children are watching .
[ MAN 'S VOICE ECHOING ] Haven 't they taught you ? Knock before you enter .
[ WOMAN 'S VOICE ECHOING ] Knock before you enter .
[ MAN 'S VOICE ECHOING ] Knock before you enter .
[ OVERLAPPING ECHOING VOICES ]
[ OVERLAPPING , ECHOING INTENSIFY ]
WOMAN 'S VOICE : Love me ! Love me ! Love me !
Love me ! Love me ! [ SCREAMS ]
[ CHILDREN LAUGHING ]
MRS. GROSE 'S VOICE : Quint is dead .
Flora !
[ WHISPERING ] Somebody 's walking in the garden .
[ ECHOING ] Miles !
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
Oh !
Miles , what were you doing ?
- When ? - You were looking up at the tower .
- You saw something . - Of course I did .
- What did you see ? - Only you , Miss Giddens .
- I was waiting for you . - Waiting ?
Oh , I knew you 'd look out . But don 't you want to know why ?
- [ SIGHS ] - I 'll tell you the real , true reason .
- But I wonder if you 'll understand . - I 'll try .
Well , put me back to bed then , if you 're not too cross .
- Are you cross ? - Yes , I am .
I thought you would be . Come on . I 'll tell you when I 'm in bed .
- Well , now ... - Yes ?
I wanted you to think me bad for a change .
For a change ?
Well , I thought I might be becoming a bore .
Miles , tell me the truth .
But I am . I mean , good children do get a bit boring , don 't they ?
So I thought , why not go out tonight and wander about in my bare feet ?
It was a shocking thing to do , wasn 't it ?
Yes , very shocking .
Well , that was our plan . Flora and I arranged it together .
But we giggled so . I was sure you must have heard us .
Yes , I ... I did hear something .
I told her to go over to the window ...
then you 'd be bound to look out and see me .
Flora 's been bad as well .
Miles , what are you hiding under your pillow ?
I 'm not hiding it . I 'm keeping it warm .
I found it this morning , one of my pigeons .
I couldn 't , could I , leave it out there alone ?
But , Miles ...
its neck .
- It looks as though ... - Someone had broken it .
Yes , poor thing . I 'll bury it tomorrow .
Kiss me good night , Miss Giddens .
[ INHALES DEEPLY ]
[ EXHALES ]
[ PIANO : " O WILLOW WALY " ]
Are you writing to your sister , Miss Giddens ?
No , Miles , to your uncle .
I knew you would finally .
Did you ?
I suppose you 're telling him what a wicked boy I 've been .
It concerns you , in part , yes .
Well , do be sure and give him my love .
Miles , isn 't that the tune that Flora 's always singing ?
- Do you like it ? - [ CONTINUES ]
Where is Flora ?
Isn 't she here ?
Shall I play you something else ?
- Flora ! - [ CONTINUES ]
Flora !
- Flora ! - [ RUNNING FOOTSTEPS ]
Mrs. Grose ! Mrs. Grose ! Flora , she 's gone ! Miles planned it beautifully .
Oh , yes , it was very clever . Quick , we must find her .
- Where ? - By the lake where we picnic .
Where we saw Miss Jessel !
- You see ? She 's taken the boat . - All alone , that child ?
She 's not alone . And at such time , she 's not a child .
- She 's an old , old woman . - [ ROLLING THUNDER ]
[ MUSIC BOX : " O WILLOW WALY " ]
[ CONTINUES ]
[ THUNDERCLAP ]
[ ENDS ]
- Flora ? - Oh , there you are .
I thought someone was watching me .
And who did you think it was ?
Why , Miss Giddens , you came out without your hat .
- So did you . - [ THUNDERCLAP ]
- How did you get here , dear ? - In the boat .
MRS. GROSE : Miss ? Miss Giddens ?
And when did you learn to row , Flora ?
Miles taught me .
Why did you come here ?
I always come here when I want to dance , when I want to be alone .
And who gave you that music box ?
- I don 't think I remember . - Miss Giddens ?
Oh , yes , I do . It was Mrs. Grose .
- No , it was not . - Wasn 't it , Miss Giddens , dear ?
And where , my pet , is Miss Jessel ?
- [ THUNDERCLAP ] - Where is she , Flora ?
Miss Giddens ?
Where is she ? You know you can see her !
- Miss ? - Look , Flora , look ! There !
- You know you can see her . - I can 't ! I can 't !
Admit it ! She 's there ! You know you can see her !
- I can 't ! I can 't ! - But look ! She 's there !
- Stop it ! I 'm frightened ! - Stop it , miss .
[ FLORA SOBBING ]
- But you can see her . You must ! - [ FLORA SCREAMING ]
Hush , hush , dear . She isn 't there . How could she be ?
She 's dead and buried . Hush , little lamb .
I can 't see anything ! I 've never seen anything ! You 're cruel ! You 're wicked !
I hate you ! I hate you ! I hate you !
- Flora ! - Take me away from her .
She 's cruel ! Take me away ! Please take me away !
Don 't look at her ! Don 't look at her ! She frightens me so !
- [ SCREAMS ] - Hush , dear . Come on .
- [ SCREAMING , SOBBING ] - Mrs. Grose !
[ SCREAMING , SOBBING CONTINUES ]
Come along .
[ THUNDERCLAP ]
[ SCREAMING CONTINUES ]
[ SCREAMING , SOBBING CONTINUES ]
I like it when the fire does that . Don 't you ?
[ FLORA SCREAMING , SOBBING ]
[ SCREAMING , SOBBING CONTINUES ]
MRS. GROSE : Shh . Hush , my love . Anna will stay with you .
[ SCREAMING CONTINUES ]
I 've never known the equal . Never . It 's beyond nature .
Now do you believe me ? Now that you 've seen ?
Now that I 've heard . In all my years ...
and I 've known a vile tongue or two in my time , never have I heard such obscenities .
- [ SCREAMING , SOBBING CONTINUES ] - That pleases you ?
No , of course not , but it justifies me . It 's proof .
Perhaps it is , but to hear such filth from a child 's mouth ...
I don 't know where she could have learned such language .
- I know . - I never heard her speak like it before .
- Never . Till you came . - You saw who taught her .
- You saw that woman . - I know what I saw .
Has she mentioned it ? Mentioned Miss Jessel ?
- Only to say there was no one there . - You pretended to believe her .
I didn 't have to pretend .
Well , how can you say that ?
As though you ... you too were a complete innocent ?
Well , you lived here . You knew those two .
You knew them when they were alive , and what influence they were on the children .
And it frightened you . When I came here , you were still frightened .
Oh , you were . I sensed it . And why ?
Because you felt they weren 't really dead .
And now , despite all that , you turn on me . You blame me .
And all I want to do is save the children , not destroy them . Don 't you know that ?
All I know is Miss Flora was a sweet , innocent child ...
a happy child , until you made her face that ...
- That woman ! Say it ! - That bad memory !
[ FLORA SCREAMS , SOBBING ]
It may have been the saving of her .
[ EXHALES ] But you must take her to her uncle .
You must both go away tomorrow .
Away from me , away from them , the servants ... everyone must go .
Leave you here all alone ?
Except for Miles .
We were together this afternoon ...
sitting in front of the fire .
He didn 't say anything ...
but he wanted to .
It was like a pendulum ...
and I could feel it swinging my way .
Slowly , slowly .
Oh , yes , he wanted to reveal himself and ask for my help .
And we must give him that chance . Don 't you understand that ?
After today , miss , I doubt I shall ever understand you .
It was a cruel thing . And if you 're planning another cruelty ...
But to wake a child out of a bad dream , is that a cruelty ?
[ SIGHS ] If you were my age ...
and had cared for as many children as I have ...
you 'd know that waking a child can sometimes be worse than any bad dream .
- No . - It 's the shock .
And then being suddenly deprived .
No , you 're wrong . You 're talking nonsense .
As you say , miss .
You and Flora will leave tomorrow .
It is my decision . I shall send the servants away .
He put me in charge ... in sole charge , Mrs. Grose .
Tomorrow I must be alone here with Miles .
Miss , may I ask what I am to tell their uncle ?
The truth .
The truth ?
Yes , miss . Thank you .
Mrs. Grose , have you got my letter ?
- What letter , miss ? - To their uncle . I left it on the desk .
Oh , I haven 't touched it , miss .
Well , I wonder who ...
Oh , of course ... Miles .
- You 're accusing him of stealing ? - Well , what matter .
It 's just one thing more for us to talk about when we 're alone .
- Where is Master Miles ? - He went out early this morning .
But I shall wait for him .
He 'll come to me .
Well , I ... I suppose Miss Flora and I had best be on our way .
Give her my love ...
when she 's better .
And , Mrs. Grose , please , wait till you see Miles again ...
before you judge me .
I can 't judge you , miss .
A body can only judge themselves .
May God be with you , miss .
[ DOOR OPENS , CLOSES ]
[ BIRDS SQUAWKING ]
[ WHIP CRACKS ]
[ TICKING ]
[ ROLLING THUNDER ]
[ BIRD SQUAWKING ]
So , here you are .
I say , are we having tea in here ?
- Yes , Miles . - How very grand and grown-up .
Yes , and we can talk together now , like adults .
Jolly nice , I call it .
I feel quite the master of the house .
Where are the servants ?
They 've gone home .
Oh , did you send them , or did they take fright and run away ?
What do you mean ?
Well , you 're afraid , and perhaps you made them so .
And of what ... assuming you are right ...
of what am I afraid , Miles ?
I 'm not a mind reader , my dear . I 've told you that before .
But I do sense things .
Don 't worry . There 's a man in the house .
Is there ?
Yes , me . I 'll protect you .
[ CHUCKLES ] I say , it is fun .
We 've got the whole house to ourselves .
More or less . There are still the others .
Poor Flora . Is she awfully ill ?
I mean , is it serious ?
Has she gone to hospital ?
No , just to London .
I think Bly didn 't agree with her anymore .
- This house upset her . - Suddenly ?
Oh , no , I had seen it coming on .
Did you ? Then why didn 't I ?
I love Flora , and I know what she feels before she feels it herself .
She loved this house .
She was as happy here ...
As happy as I am .
Are you ?
- What ? - So very happy .
Are you , Miles ?
If you 'll excuse me .
- Miles , you haven 't ... - [ DOOR CLOSES ]
Poor Flora . She must have been upset to have forgotten Rupert .
Why did you want to be alone with me ?
I think you know very well .
What do I know ?
Or rather , what is it that you want to know ?
Well , for one thing , why that night when you were supposed to be in bed ...
- why were you in the garden ? - I told you .
The real reason , Miles .
It 's beyond me why you go on asking a fellow questions ...
when every time he answers you you tell him it isn 't true .
Because you are not telling the truth .
Don 't shout . Don 't be so angry .
It does something to your face .
It makes you look ugly and cruel .
Miles . Miles , listen to me .
I 'm not a cruel person .
I 'm sometimes very foolish and I make mistakes ...
but I 'm not cruel .
My father taught me to love people and help them .
Help them even if they refuse my help .
Even if it hurt them sometimes .
And that 's the only reason I 'm here is to help you .
Whatever you 've done , I 'm not against you .
- I don 't think it 's your fault . - But I haven 't done anything .
Then why were you sent home from school ?
It must be because I 'm different .
But you aren 't . You 're like any other boy .
Ah , now who isn 't telling the truth ?
If you really thought that , we wouldn 't be having these conversations .
No , my dear , you don 't think I 'm like any other boy .
That 's why you 're afraid .
If I am , it 's for you .
And I am afraid for you , Miles .
- If you don 't tell me now ... - There 's nothing .
Isn 't there ? Why did you take my letter ?
You did take it , didn 't you ?
Yes , I took it .
Why ?
To see what you said about us .
- Us ? - [ RUSTLING ]
Well , about me .
- [ RUSTLING ] - And what did you discover ?
You thanked my uncle for trusting you .
You apologized for troubling him ...
for asking him to come down .
Go on , Miles . What else did I say ?
That 's all I read . I heard footsteps . I threw it on the fire .
And did you take other things ?
Is that what you did at school ?
No , I 'm not a thief .
Then what did you do , Miles ?
I ... Well , I ... I said things .
Yes , Miles ?
Sometimes I hurt things .
And sometimes at night ...
when everything was dark ...
- What ? - They screamed .
The masters heard about it .
They said I frightened the other boys .
And when ...
did you first see and hear of such things ?
Why , I ... I made them up .
Who taught them to you ?
I told you , they just came into my head .
What were they ?
Shall I tell you who taught them to you ?
I won 't ever again . I promise .
Shall I tell you who taught you the things you 've done , the things you 've said ?
- Shall I tell you his name ? - You don 't fool me .
- I know why you keep on and on . - [ GASPS ]
It 's because you 're afraid . You 're afraid you might be mad .
So you keep on and on , trying to make me admit something that isn 't true .
Trying to frighten me the way you frightened Flora .
- Miles . - But I 'm not Flora . I 'm no baby .
You think you can run to my uncle with a lot of lies .
But he won 't believe you , not when I tell him what you are ...
a damned hussy , a damned dirty-minded hag !
You never fooled us . We always knew . [ LAUGHS ]
- Miles ? - Forgive me .
Hush , darling , hush .
- There . - I didn 't mean it .
Oh , it wasn 't you .
That voice , those words ...
they weren 't yours .
[ SOBBING ] Forgive me .
Oh , Miles .
Dear Miles , say it now .
Now , while I 'm holding you .
Say his name ...
and it will all be over .
Who ?
The man who taught you .
The man you 've been meeting ...
that you 've never stopped meeting .
You 're wrong ! You 're insane !
- You 're insane ! You 're insane ! - His name , Miles !
His name , Miles . Tell me his name !
- You must tell me his name ! - He 's dead !
- Look ! Miles , look ! - [ MILES SCREAMS ]
- Look ! - No !
- He 's here ! For the last time , he 's here ! - No , no , he 's dead !
He 's here , and you must say his name !
Quint ! Peter Quint ! Where ? Where ?
Where ? Where , you devil ?
Where ?
[ NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE ]
- He 's gone , Miles . - [ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
You 're safe .
You 're free .
I have you .
He 's lost you forever .
Miles ?
[ CHIRPING CONTINUES ]
Miles !
Oh !
Oh , no .
[ CHIRPING CONTINUES ]